Alexis Enmanuel De Los Santos Báez

(+1) 829 677-3363 alexisenmanuel@live.com linkedin.com/in/alexisdelossantos

Software Engineer | Front-End Web Developer

Time Zone: GMT-4

Software engineer, with more than 2 years of experience as Front-End Developer in the development of web applications, focused on the best solutions to customer needs and creating clean and reusable code, among the technologies that I master are JavaScript, HTML / CSS, React, Node JS, Bootstrap and SQL. I am self-taught, very willing to learn and proactive.

EXPERIENCE

-Ecommerce and Websites (2018-2022):

Online stores for businesses, clothing stores, cosmetic stores, department stores, etc...

- 25% increase of the shopping cart with cross selling and improve shopping experience by 95%.
- Reduced dissatisfaction with the usability of the website by 30%.

Tech-stack: JavaScript, React, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Node JS, PHP, MySQL, WordPress.

-Complaints and Suggestions Tracking System (2020):

It is a system that allows knowledge of different complaints and requests from interested groups and permits monitoring and management of solutions for users.

- Development of the entire software life cycle and Project Leader (3 software developers).
- Reduced the cost by 25% by reducing congestion and print and telephone communications.
- 95% improvement in the satisfaction with processes for sending complaints and suggestions
- 90% reduction in the working time spent on managing complaints and suggestions.
- Facilitated 95% management and 60% the entity's perception of the status of complaints.

Tech-stack: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, PHP, MySQL.

-Election voting simulation application (2019):

Simulator web application of automated electoral votes:

- Development of the entire software life cycle.
- Increased candidate recognition by 70%.

Tech-stack: Javascript, HTML, CSS, PHP, MySQL.

-Equipment lubrication maintenance system (2017-2018):

Desktop system designed to keep track of maintenance plans for industrial machinery.

- Development of the entire software life cycle and Project Leader (3 software developers).
- Reduced maintenance costs by up to 40% and inventory level by 60%.
- Achieved a 35% increase in equipment life.

Tech-stack: C#, Microsoft SQL Server.

SKILLS

-Technologies: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Node JS, Bootstrap, SQL, GIT, WordPress, API Rest.

-Frameworks and Libraries: React, Bootstrap.

-Languages: Spanish, native; English, B1 (CEFR).

EDUCATION AND CERTIFICATIONS

-Escuela Organizacional Industrial; Madrid, Spain Master in Artificial Intelligence 2021-2022

-**UAPA**; Santiago, Dominican Republic *Software Engineering 2016-2020*

-Infotep; Santiago, Dominican Republic
Diseño Web 2018

-PLATZI; JavaScript School 2020

Frontend Developer | CSS Grid Layout | Ecmascript 6+ | Asynchronism with JavaScript | JavaScript Professional | React JS | Webpack | React Router y Redux | Node.js Fundamentals | Backend with Node.js | Server Side Render with Express.js | Authentication with Passport.js | Backend and Frontend Integration